<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-01-22T09:19:46-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">GovFresh</title><subtitle>Public service with and by the people.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">U.S. government, technology community advance open source security collaboration efforts</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/radar/white-house-open-source-security-summit" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="U.S. government, technology community advance open source security collaboration efforts" /><published>2022-01-14T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-01-14T10:24:08-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/radar/white-house-open-source-security-summit</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/radar/white-house-open-source-security-summit">&lt;p&gt;In the wake of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Log4j&quot;&gt;Log4j vulnerability&lt;/a&gt;, the White House met with technology companies and organizations to discuss how the federal government and industry can better partner on open source security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prior to the White House Open Source Software Security Summit, a senior administration official &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cyberscoop.com/white-house-log4j-open-source-software-security/&quot;&gt;told CyberScoop&lt;/a&gt;, “Building on the Log4j incident, the objective of this meeting is to facilitate an important discussion to improve the security of open source software — and to brainstorm how new collaboration could rapidly drive improvements.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to CyberScoop, the full tech participant list included Akamai, Amazon, Apache Software Foundation, Apple, Cloudflare, Facebook/Meta, GitHub, Google, IBM, Linux Open Source Foundation, Microsoft, Oracle, RedHat and VMware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;U.S. Commerce Secretary Gina Raimondo said the National Institute of Standards and Technology is working to gather ideas from technology and open source communities on how best to work together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“NIST intends to soon release a Request for Information asking stakeholders – people like you – how it can improve its cybersecurity efforts,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.commerce.gov/news/speeches/2022/01/remarks-us-commerce-secretary-gina-m-raimondo-white-house-open-source&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; Raimondo. “This will help ensure that NIST is partnering effectively with both the private and public sectors on cybersecurity, including open-source software.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Companies and organizations released statements expressing their commitment to collaborating with government to build stronger communities related to open source security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openssf.org/blog/2022/01/13/the-openssf-and-the-linux-foundation-address-software-supply-chain-security-challenges-at-white-house-summit/&quot;&gt;OpenSSF / Linux Foundation&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The open source ecosystem will need to work together to further cybersecurity research, training, analysis and remediation of defects found in critical open source software projects. These plans were met with positive feedback and a growing, collective commitment to take meaningful action. Following the recent log4j crisis, the time has never been more pressing for public and private collaboration to ensure that open source software components and the software supply chains they flow through demonstrate the highest cybersecurity integrity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.blog/2022-01-13-open-source-software-security-summit-securing-the-worlds-code-together/&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We see tremendous opportunity ahead to help the community realize a safer and more secure future for software. Through partnerships with governments, academia, developers, and other organizations, we can better protect and support the developers and software that power our world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.google/technology/safety-security/making-open-source-software-safer-and-more-secure/&quot;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Many leading companies and organizations don’t recognize how many parts of their critical infrastructure depend on open source. That’s why it’s essential that we see more public and private investment in keeping that ecosystem healthy and secure. … Given the importance of digital infrastructure in our lives, it’s time to start thinking of it in the same way we do our physical infrastructure. Open source software is a connective tissue for much of the online world — it deserves the same focus and funding we give to our roads and bridges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>Luke Fretwell</name></author><category term="[&quot;Digital&quot;, &quot;Open&quot;, &quot;Security&quot;]" /><summary type="html">In the wake of the Log4j vulnerability, the White House met with technology companies and organizations to discuss how the federal government and industry can better partner on open source security.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">California is working with six states to re-use code from its vaccine records portal</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/radar/california-digital-vaccine-record" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="California is working with six states to re-use code from its vaccine records portal" /><published>2022-01-09T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-01-09T16:42:32-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/radar/california-digital-vaccine-record</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/radar/california-digital-vaccine-record">&lt;p&gt;California Chief Technology Innovation Officer Rick Klau reports that 6.5 million residents have downloaded more than 11 million digital vaccine records from the state’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://myvaccinerecord.cdph.ca.gov/&quot;&gt;vaccine record portal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Klau says the state made the portal code base publicly available for re-use, and Washington state re-purposed it for its own vaccine records website. The state is working with other states to do the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the &lt;a href=&quot;https://techblog.cdt.ca.gov/2022/01/californians-have-downloaded-over-11-million-digital-vaccine-records/&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In September 2021, we released all of the code we wrote for our DCVR Portal to the public domain. Our hope at the time was that other states might take our code and implement their own system for their residents. Less than two months later, Washington State did just that, releasing WAVerify to enable Washington residents to retrieve their own digital vaccine record. Washington went a step further, making a number of improvements to our code, including adding dozens of additional translations to make the service more accessible for additional communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As we look ahead to 2022, we’re in touch with another six states who plan on following Washington’s lead, bringing code originally developed in California to even more Americans in the next few months. We put together a playbook that documented some of what we learned this year as we built and shipped the DCVR Portal, and expect other states may find it instructive as they explore doing something similar to what we did in California.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>Luke Fretwell</name></author><category term="[&quot;Digital&quot;, &quot;Open&quot;]" /><summary type="html">California Chief Technology Innovation Officer Rick Klau reports that 6.5 million residents have downloaded more than 11 million digital vaccine records from the state’s vaccine record portal.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CDO Council retrospects 2021, publishes data playbook</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/radar/cdo-council-2021-playbook" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CDO Council retrospects 2021, publishes data playbook" /><published>2022-01-03T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-01-09T16:42:32-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/radar/cdo-council-2021-playbook</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/radar/cdo-council-2021-playbook">&lt;p&gt;The Federal Chief Data Officers Council &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cdo.gov/news/celebrating-2021/&quot;&gt;shared&lt;/a&gt; its 2021 accomplishments and published a playbook to help CDOs “lead data-driven transformation” within their agencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the playbook:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;CDOs must seize opportunities to leverage data as a strategic asset within their
organization, otherwise, the CDO faces the risk of becoming a compliance driven
position. The CDO should first focus on finding opportunities to promote
the sharing and access of data within their agencies. They must build critical
relationships and show value in the near-term through “quick wins,” as data
governance and master data management programs take longer to implement
and demonstrate results. It is a hard job with a value proposition not consistently
appreciated and with challenges that are critical to overcome to properly serve their stakeholders and the American people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://resources.data.gov/assets/documents/CDO_Playbook_2021.pdf&quot;&gt;Playbook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Luke Fretwell</name></author><category term="[&quot;Data&quot;, &quot;Digital&quot;]" /><summary type="html">The Federal Chief Data Officers Council shared its 2021 accomplishments and published a playbook to help CDOs “lead data-driven transformation” within their agencies.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Public gives NASA ideas for engaging untapped communities</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/radar/nasa-engagement-underserved-communities" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Public gives NASA ideas for engaging untapped communities" /><published>2021-12-09T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-01-09T16:42:32-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/radar/nasa-engagement-underserved-communities</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/radar/nasa-engagement-underserved-communities">&lt;p&gt;NASA received 195 comments from the public in respose to a June 2021 request for information entitled, “Advancing Racial Equity and Support for Underserved Communities in NASA Programs, Contracts and Grants.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nasa.gov/press-release/public-provides-nasa-ideas-for-engaging-untapped-communities&quot;&gt;release&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;NASA requested public feedback about how it can provide underserved communities with equal access to the opportunities the agency creates. NASA specifically asked for feedback on possible opportunities to leverage NASA assets to help underserved communities, and barriers to accessing current NASA grants, programs, and procurements. The agency also worked to engage with organizations and individuals from underserved and underrepresented communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/atoms/files/rfi_response_for_eo_13985-11-23-21.pdf&quot;&gt;Responses to Mission Equity RFI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Luke Fretwell</name></author><category term="[&quot;Community&quot;, &quot;Data&quot;]" /><summary type="html">NASA received 195 comments from the public in respose to a June 2021 request for information entitled, “Advancing Racial Equity and Support for Underserved Communities in NASA Programs, Contracts and Grants.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">GAO recommends the creation of a federal digital service academy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/radar/gao-digital-services-academy" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="GAO recommends the creation of a federal digital service academy" /><published>2021-11-27T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-11-27T10:36:06-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/radar/gao-digital-services-academy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/radar/gao-digital-services-academy">&lt;p&gt;To help the federal government address challenges in technical hiring, managing and staff retention, the U.S. Government Accountability Office recommends the creation of a digital service academy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The recommendations were published in a report, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gao.gov/products/gao-22-105388&quot;&gt;Digital Services: Considerations for a Federal Academy to Develop a Pipeline of Digital Staff&lt;/a&gt;, based on an October 2021 roundtable made up of “chief technology officers, chief data officers, chief information officers, and those in similar roles across the federal government, as well as knowledgeable representatives from academia and nonprofits.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the report:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This report summarizes the perspectives that selected technology leaders shared on (1) federal workforce needs for digital services staff, (2) key characteristics of a digital service academy, and (3) considerations to help ensure federal agencies can absorb graduates of a digital service academy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;One potential method for developing digital services staff, discussed by the roundtable participants, is the creation of a digital service academy—similar to military academies—to train future civil servants in the digital skills needed to modernize government. Considerations for a digital service academy include the kinds of skills that would be taught and the composition and size of a graduating class, according to roundtable participants. Further, they said digital services staff would need proficiency in both digital skills as well understanding the functions of government to meet agencies’ needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Report: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gao.gov/products/gao-22-105388&quot;&gt;Digital Services: Considerations for a Federal Academy to Develop a Pipeline of Digital Staff&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Luke Fretwell</name></author><category term="[&quot;Data&quot;, &quot;Digital&quot;, &quot;Security&quot;]" /><summary type="html">To help the federal government address challenges in technical hiring, managing and staff retention, the U.S. Government Accountability Office recommends the creation of a digital service academy.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Census to host Open Innovation for All virtual summit</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/radar/top-open-innovation-summit-2021" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Census to host Open Innovation for All virtual summit" /><published>2021-11-26T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-11-26T17:34:01-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/radar/top-open-innovation-summit-2021</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/radar/top-open-innovation-summit-2021">&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Census Bureau and Census Open Innovation Labs will host &lt;a href=&quot;https://emamo.com/event/TOPSummit2021&quot;&gt;The Opportunity Project Summit: Open Innovation for All&lt;/a&gt; December 13-15. The event is virtual and free to all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From TOP:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Much of the Summit will showcase the work of hundreds of participants in this year’s The Opportunity Project (TOP) sprints. TOP is a leading federal innovation model that brings cross-sector partners together to solve problems for people nationwide, using federal open data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This year, 7 federal agencies (the U.S. Census Bureau, HHS, NOAA, MBDA, Treasury, CFPB, and HUD) and 2 cities (New York and Coral Gables, FL) led TOP sprints focused on the World Post-COVID-19. We’ll feature the resulting new products and announce more than $300,000 in awards to the winners of the Open Data for Good Grand Challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talks include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data Tools Helping to Illuminate New Economic Patterns&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;TED-Style Talks: Data Art and Non-traditional Tech Education&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A Data- and Human-Centered Conversation on Addressing Homelessness&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Equidad e inclusividad”: Technology to Support Language Access and Minority Inclusion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;TED-Style Talks: Technology and Justice, the New Economy and the American Dream&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What Is Data Equity? A Plain-language Discussion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let’s Get “Climate Smart”: How Tech Can Boost Community Resilience to Climate Change&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Government Tech Funding 101&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Interactive Workshop: Bureaucracy Hacking Masterclass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://emamo.com/event/TOPSummit2021&quot;&gt;Register&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Luke Fretwell</name></author><category term="[&quot;Data&quot;, &quot;Digital&quot;, &quot;Open&quot;, &quot;Security&quot;]" /><summary type="html">The U.S. Census Bureau and Census Open Innovation Labs will host The Opportunity Project Summit: Open Innovation for All December 13-15. The event is virtual and free to all.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Federal government publishes cybersecurity incident and vulnerability playbooks</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/radar/federal-government-cybersecurity-incident-vulnerability-response-playbooks" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Federal government publishes cybersecurity incident and vulnerability playbooks" /><published>2021-11-18T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-11-18T19:06:23-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/radar/federal-government-cybersecurity-incident-vulnerability-response-playbooks</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/radar/federal-government-cybersecurity-incident-vulnerability-response-playbooks">&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Department of Homeland Security’s Cybersecurity &amp;amp; Infrastructure Security Agency has published &lt;a href=&quot;https://us-cert.cisa.gov/ncas/current-activity/2021/11/16/new-federal-government-cybersecurity-incident-and-vulnerability&quot;&gt;Federal Government Cybersecurity Incident and Vulnerability Response Playbooks&lt;/a&gt; to “provide federal civilian executive branch agencies with operational procedures for planning and conducting cybersecurity incident and vulnerability response activities.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Although CISA created the playbooks for FCEB agencies, we encourage critical infrastructure entities; state, local, territorial, and tribal government organizations; and private sector organizations to review them to benchmark their own vulnerability and incident response practices,” says CISA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The playbooks are in response to the White House &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/05/12/executive-order-on-improving-the-nations-cybersecurity/&quot;&gt;Executive Order (EO) 14028: Improving the Nation’s Cybersecurity&lt;/a&gt; focused on removing barriers to sharing threat information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nextgov.com/cybersecurity/2021/11/cisa-launches-government-cybersecurity-incident-and-vulnerability-response-playbooks/186869/&quot;&gt;NextGov&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fedscoop.com/cisa-issues-cybersecurity-incident-vulnerability-response-playbooks-for-federal-agencies/&quot;&gt;FedScoop&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Luke Fretwell</name></author><category term="[&quot;Digital&quot;, &quot;Security&quot;]" /><summary type="html">The U.S. Department of Homeland Security’s Cybersecurity &amp;amp; Infrastructure Security Agency has published Federal Government Cybersecurity Incident and Vulnerability Response Playbooks to “provide federal civilian executive branch agencies with operational procedures for planning and conducting cybersecurity incident and vulnerability response activities.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Defense Innovation Unit publishes responsible AI guidelines</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/radar/diu-responsible-ai-guidelines" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Defense Innovation Unit publishes responsible AI guidelines" /><published>2021-11-18T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-11-18T19:06:23-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/radar/diu-responsible-ai-guidelines</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/radar/diu-responsible-ai-guidelines">&lt;p&gt;The Defense Innovation Unit published &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.diu.mil/responsible-ai-guidelines&quot;&gt;Responsible AI Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; to help the Defense Department operationalize ethical principles for artificial intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“DIU’s RAI Guidelines provide a step-by-step framework for AI companies, DoD stakeholders, and program managers that can help to ensure that AI programs align with the DoD’s Ethical Principles for AI and that fairness, accountability and transparency are considered at each step in the development cycle of an AI system,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.diu.mil/latest/diu-operationalizes-responsible-ai-guidelines-in-practice&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; Dr. Jared Dunnmon, technical director of the AI/ML portfolio at DIU.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the &lt;a href=&quot;https://assets.ctfassets.net/3nanhbfkr0pc/acoo1Fj5uungnGNPJ3QWy/6ec382b3b5a20ec7de6defdb33b04dcd/2021_RAI_Report.pdf&quot;&gt;guidelines&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;dod-ethical-principles-for-artificial-intelligence&quot;&gt;DoD Ethical Principles for Artificial Intelligence&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Responsible.&lt;/strong&gt; DoD personnel will exercise appropriate levels of judgment and care, while remaining responsible for the development, deployment, and use of AI capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Equitable.&lt;/strong&gt; The Department will take deliberate steps to minimize unintended bias in AI capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Traceable.&lt;/strong&gt; The Department’s AI capabilities will be developed and deployed such that relevant personnel possess an appropriate understanding of the technology, development processes, and operational methods applicable to AI capabilities, including with transparent and auditable methodologies, data  sources, and design procedure and documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reliable.&lt;/strong&gt; The Department’s AI capabilities will have explicit, well-defined uses, and the safety, security, and effectiveness of such capabilities will be subject to testing and assurance within those defined uses across their entire life-cycles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Governable.&lt;/strong&gt; The Department will design and engineer AI capabilities to  fulfill their intended functions while possessing the ability to detect and avoid unintended consequences, and the ability to disengage or deactivate deployed systems that demonstrate unintended behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>Luke Fretwell</name></author><category term="[&quot;Digital&quot;, &quot;Inclusion&quot;, &quot;Security&quot;]" /><summary type="html">The Defense Innovation Unit published Responsible AI Guidelines to help the Defense Department operationalize ethical principles for artificial intelligence.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Data Coalition makes recommendations to the Chief Data Officers Council</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/radar/data-coalition-recommendations-chief-data-officers-council" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Data Coalition makes recommendations to the Chief Data Officers Council" /><published>2021-11-17T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-11-17T17:08:03-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/radar/data-coalition-recommendations-chief-data-officers-council</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/radar/data-coalition-recommendations-chief-data-officers-council">&lt;p&gt;In response to a Chief Data Officers Council &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2021/10/14/2021-22267/office-of-shared-solutions-and-performance-improvement-osspi-chief-data-officers-council-cdo-request&quot;&gt;call for public feedback&lt;/a&gt;, the Data Coalition shared &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.datacoalition.org/12-recommendations-for-the-chief-data-officers-council/&quot;&gt;its recommendations&lt;/a&gt; on how the federal government can best leverage data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The success of CDOs in the federal government hinges on their ability to perform expected and critical tasks,” said Data Foundation President Nicholas Hart in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.datacoalition.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/CDO-RFI-2.pdf&quot;&gt;letter&lt;/a&gt; to the CDO Council. “If they are successful, government data can be an asset, creating a robust data infrastructure that will serve a variety of purposes, including improving operational decision-making and evidence-based policymaking capabilities.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recommendations, based on a Data Coalition &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.datacoalition.org/event/forum-cdo-mission-and-vision-2021/&quot;&gt;virtual public forum&lt;/a&gt; and Data Foundation &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.datafoundation.org/cdo-insights-report-2021&quot;&gt;survey&lt;/a&gt;, include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CDOs should work with their agency CFO and OMB to increase CDO funding flexibilities and direct resources.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CDOs should work with OMB to clarify responsibilities and expectations.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Congress should remove the statutory sunset of the CDO Council.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The CDO Council should work to create an ecosystem of data-literate and data-fluent workers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CDOs should emphasize their role as designated leaders to promote training and data fluency among staff of departments.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The CDO Council should work with the OMB to ensure that forthcoming implementation guidance to agencies on data inventories prioritizes machine readability and interoperability.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CDOs should focus on data sharing standards that facilitate interoperability, data linkage, and privacy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Publicly accessible data must be prioritized.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CDOs can improve communication about how they demonstrate the value of using data.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CDOs should conduct regular maturity assessments to accurately gauge existing data capacity and needs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The CDO Council should create a permanent data ethics working group to ensure the Data Ethics framework continuously meets emerging needs, to provide resources and guidance to agencies, and to partner with relevant professional associations for ongoing education and training on data ethics.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The CDO Council should work with CIOs to facilitate the adoption of appropriate modernized technology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Luke Fretwell</name></author><category term="[&quot;Digital&quot;, &quot;Data&quot;]" /><summary type="html">In response to a Chief Data Officers Council call for public feedback, the Data Coalition shared its recommendations on how the federal government can best leverage data.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">NIST wants public feedback on cybersecurity labeling for consumer software</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/radar/nist-public-input-cybersecurity-consumer-software-labeling" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="NIST wants public feedback on cybersecurity labeling for consumer software" /><published>2021-11-03T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-11-15T13:24:01-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/radar/nist-public-input-cybersecurity-consumer-software-labeling</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/radar/nist-public-input-cybersecurity-consumer-software-labeling">&lt;p&gt;The National Institute of Standards and Technology has drafted a set of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nist.gov/itl/executive-order-improving-nations-cybersecurity/consumer-software-criteria&quot;&gt;cybersecurity criteria&lt;/a&gt; to help consumers make more informed software purchasing decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NIST says it doesn’t intend to create a formal standard, but hopes to create a voluntary labeling system that shows the software “incorporates a baseline level of security measures.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From NIST:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The document, formally titled &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nist.gov/document/draft-baseline-criteria-consumer-software-cybersecurity-labeling&quot;&gt;Draft Baseline Criteria for Consumer Software Cybersecurity Labeling&lt;/a&gt;, forms part of NIST’s response to the May 12, 2021, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2021/05/17/2021-10460/improving-the-nations-cybersecurity&quot;&gt;Executive Order (EO) 14028 on Improving the Nation’s Cybersecurity&lt;/a&gt;. The EO specifies that NIST “shall identify secure software development practices or criteria for a consumer software labeling program” — criteria that reflect a baseline level of cybersecurity and that focus on ease of use for consumers. (The EO also instructs NIST to initiate a labeling effort on the cybersecurity aspects of consumer devices associated with the Internet of Things, which the present publication does not address.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the announcement, NIST acknowledged the challenges of a security labeling system for a wide array of technology solutions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Part of the challenge is the sheer vastness and variety of the consumer software landscape. Software forms an integral part of most consumers’ lives, and it is subject to vulnerabilities that place the users’ safety, property and productivity at risk — but there is no one-size-fits-all approach to cybersecurity that can be applied to all types of consumer software. The cybersecurity considerations for a smartphone game could differ greatly from, for example, those applied to a banking app. Yet a security label aimed at consumers will need to communicate simply and directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comments on the draft document are due by December 16, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Luke Fretwell</name></author><category term="[&quot;Digital&quot;, &quot;Security&quot;]" /><summary type="html">The National Institute of Standards and Technology has drafted a set of cybersecurity criteria to help consumers make more informed software purchasing decisions.</summary></entry></feed>