<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-12-04T08:45:59-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">GovFresh</title><subtitle>Public service with and by the people.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">GAO recommends the creation of a federal digital service academy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/radar/gao-digital-services-academy" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="GAO recommends the creation of a federal digital service academy" /><published>2021-11-27T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-11-27T10:36:06-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/radar/gao-digital-services-academy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/radar/gao-digital-services-academy">&lt;p&gt;To help the federal government address challenges in technical hiring, managing and staff retention, the U.S. Government Accountability Office recommends the creation of a digital service academy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The recommendations were published in a report, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gao.gov/products/gao-22-105388&quot;&gt;Digital Services: Considerations for a Federal Academy to Develop a Pipeline of Digital Staff&lt;/a&gt;, based on an October 2021 roundtable made up of “chief technology officers, chief data officers, chief information officers, and those in similar roles across the federal government, as well as knowledgeable representatives from academia and nonprofits.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the report:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This report summarizes the perspectives that selected technology leaders shared on (1) federal workforce needs for digital services staff, (2) key characteristics of a digital service academy, and (3) considerations to help ensure federal agencies can absorb graduates of a digital service academy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;One potential method for developing digital services staff, discussed by the roundtable participants, is the creation of a digital service academy—similar to military academies—to train future civil servants in the digital skills needed to modernize government. Considerations for a digital service academy include the kinds of skills that would be taught and the composition and size of a graduating class, according to roundtable participants. Further, they said digital services staff would need proficiency in both digital skills as well understanding the functions of government to meet agencies’ needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Report: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gao.gov/products/gao-22-105388&quot;&gt;Digital Services: Considerations for a Federal Academy to Develop a Pipeline of Digital Staff&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Luke Fretwell</name></author><category term="[&quot;Data&quot;, &quot;Digital&quot;, &quot;Security&quot;]" /><summary type="html">To help the federal government address challenges in technical hiring, managing and staff retention, the U.S. Government Accountability Office recommends the creation of a digital service academy.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Census to host Open Innovation for All virtual summit</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/radar/top-open-innovation-summit-2021" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Census to host Open Innovation for All virtual summit" /><published>2021-11-26T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-11-26T17:34:01-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/radar/top-open-innovation-summit-2021</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/radar/top-open-innovation-summit-2021">&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Census Bureau and Census Open Innovation Labs will host &lt;a href=&quot;https://emamo.com/event/TOPSummit2021&quot;&gt;The Opportunity Project Summit: Open Innovation for All&lt;/a&gt; December 13-15. The event is virtual and free to all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From TOP:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Much of the Summit will showcase the work of hundreds of participants in this year’s The Opportunity Project (TOP) sprints. TOP is a leading federal innovation model that brings cross-sector partners together to solve problems for people nationwide, using federal open data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This year, 7 federal agencies (the U.S. Census Bureau, HHS, NOAA, MBDA, Treasury, CFPB, and HUD) and 2 cities (New York and Coral Gables, FL) led TOP sprints focused on the World Post-COVID-19. We’ll feature the resulting new products and announce more than $300,000 in awards to the winners of the Open Data for Good Grand Challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talks include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data Tools Helping to Illuminate New Economic Patterns&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;TED-Style Talks: Data Art and Non-traditional Tech Education&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A Data- and Human-Centered Conversation on Addressing Homelessness&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Equidad e inclusividad”: Technology to Support Language Access and Minority Inclusion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;TED-Style Talks: Technology and Justice, the New Economy and the American Dream&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What Is Data Equity? A Plain-language Discussion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let’s Get “Climate Smart”: How Tech Can Boost Community Resilience to Climate Change&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Government Tech Funding 101&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Interactive Workshop: Bureaucracy Hacking Masterclass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://emamo.com/event/TOPSummit2021&quot;&gt;Register&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Luke Fretwell</name></author><category term="[&quot;Data&quot;, &quot;Digital&quot;, &quot;Open&quot;, &quot;Security&quot;]" /><summary type="html">The U.S. Census Bureau and Census Open Innovation Labs will host The Opportunity Project Summit: Open Innovation for All December 13-15. The event is virtual and free to all.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Federal government publishes cybersecurity incident and vulnerability playbooks</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/radar/federal-government-cybersecurity-incident-vulnerability-response-playbooks" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Federal government publishes cybersecurity incident and vulnerability playbooks" /><published>2021-11-18T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-11-18T19:06:23-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/radar/federal-government-cybersecurity-incident-vulnerability-response-playbooks</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/radar/federal-government-cybersecurity-incident-vulnerability-response-playbooks">&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Department of Homeland Security’s Cybersecurity &amp;amp; Infrastructure Security Agency has published &lt;a href=&quot;https://us-cert.cisa.gov/ncas/current-activity/2021/11/16/new-federal-government-cybersecurity-incident-and-vulnerability&quot;&gt;Federal Government Cybersecurity Incident and Vulnerability Response Playbooks&lt;/a&gt; to “provide federal civilian executive branch agencies with operational procedures for planning and conducting cybersecurity incident and vulnerability response activities.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Although CISA created the playbooks for FCEB agencies, we encourage critical infrastructure entities; state, local, territorial, and tribal government organizations; and private sector organizations to review them to benchmark their own vulnerability and incident response practices,” says CISA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The playbooks are in response to the White House &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/05/12/executive-order-on-improving-the-nations-cybersecurity/&quot;&gt;Executive Order (EO) 14028: Improving the Nation’s Cybersecurity&lt;/a&gt; focused on removing barriers to sharing threat information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nextgov.com/cybersecurity/2021/11/cisa-launches-government-cybersecurity-incident-and-vulnerability-response-playbooks/186869/&quot;&gt;NextGov&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fedscoop.com/cisa-issues-cybersecurity-incident-vulnerability-response-playbooks-for-federal-agencies/&quot;&gt;FedScoop&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Luke Fretwell</name></author><category term="[&quot;Digital&quot;, &quot;Security&quot;]" /><summary type="html">The U.S. Department of Homeland Security’s Cybersecurity &amp;amp; Infrastructure Security Agency has published Federal Government Cybersecurity Incident and Vulnerability Response Playbooks to “provide federal civilian executive branch agencies with operational procedures for planning and conducting cybersecurity incident and vulnerability response activities.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Defense Innovation Unit publishes responsible AI guidelines</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/radar/diu-responsible-ai-guidelines" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Defense Innovation Unit publishes responsible AI guidelines" /><published>2021-11-18T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-11-18T19:06:23-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/radar/diu-responsible-ai-guidelines</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/radar/diu-responsible-ai-guidelines">&lt;p&gt;The Defense Innovation Unit published &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.diu.mil/responsible-ai-guidelines&quot;&gt;Responsible AI Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; to help the Defense Department operationalize ethical principles for artificial intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“DIU’s RAI Guidelines provide a step-by-step framework for AI companies, DoD stakeholders, and program managers that can help to ensure that AI programs align with the DoD’s Ethical Principles for AI and that fairness, accountability and transparency are considered at each step in the development cycle of an AI system,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.diu.mil/latest/diu-operationalizes-responsible-ai-guidelines-in-practice&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; Dr. Jared Dunnmon, technical director of the AI/ML portfolio at DIU.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the &lt;a href=&quot;https://assets.ctfassets.net/3nanhbfkr0pc/acoo1Fj5uungnGNPJ3QWy/6ec382b3b5a20ec7de6defdb33b04dcd/2021_RAI_Report.pdf&quot;&gt;guidelines&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;dod-ethical-principles-for-artificial-intelligence&quot;&gt;DoD Ethical Principles for Artificial Intelligence&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Responsible.&lt;/strong&gt; DoD personnel will exercise appropriate levels of judgment and care, while remaining responsible for the development, deployment, and use of AI capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Equitable.&lt;/strong&gt; The Department will take deliberate steps to minimize unintended bias in AI capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Traceable.&lt;/strong&gt; The Department’s AI capabilities will be developed and deployed such that relevant personnel possess an appropriate understanding of the technology, development processes, and operational methods applicable to AI capabilities, including with transparent and auditable methodologies, data  sources, and design procedure and documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reliable.&lt;/strong&gt; The Department’s AI capabilities will have explicit, well-defined uses, and the safety, security, and effectiveness of such capabilities will be subject to testing and assurance within those defined uses across their entire life-cycles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Governable.&lt;/strong&gt; The Department will design and engineer AI capabilities to  fulfill their intended functions while possessing the ability to detect and avoid unintended consequences, and the ability to disengage or deactivate deployed systems that demonstrate unintended behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>Luke Fretwell</name></author><category term="[&quot;Digital&quot;, &quot;Inclusion&quot;, &quot;Security&quot;]" /><summary type="html">The Defense Innovation Unit published Responsible AI Guidelines to help the Defense Department operationalize ethical principles for artificial intelligence.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Data Coalition makes recommendations to the Chief Data Officers Council</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/radar/data-coalition-recommendations-chief-data-officers-council" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Data Coalition makes recommendations to the Chief Data Officers Council" /><published>2021-11-17T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-11-17T17:08:03-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/radar/data-coalition-recommendations-chief-data-officers-council</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/radar/data-coalition-recommendations-chief-data-officers-council">&lt;p&gt;In response to a Chief Data Officers Council &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2021/10/14/2021-22267/office-of-shared-solutions-and-performance-improvement-osspi-chief-data-officers-council-cdo-request&quot;&gt;call for public feedback&lt;/a&gt;, the Data Coalition shared &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.datacoalition.org/12-recommendations-for-the-chief-data-officers-council/&quot;&gt;its recommendations&lt;/a&gt; on how the federal government can best leverage data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The success of CDOs in the federal government hinges on their ability to perform expected and critical tasks,” said Data Foundation President Nicholas Hart in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.datacoalition.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/CDO-RFI-2.pdf&quot;&gt;letter&lt;/a&gt; to the CDO Council. “If they are successful, government data can be an asset, creating a robust data infrastructure that will serve a variety of purposes, including improving operational decision-making and evidence-based policymaking capabilities.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recommendations, based on a Data Coalition &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.datacoalition.org/event/forum-cdo-mission-and-vision-2021/&quot;&gt;virtual public forum&lt;/a&gt; and Data Foundation &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.datafoundation.org/cdo-insights-report-2021&quot;&gt;survey&lt;/a&gt;, include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CDOs should work with their agency CFO and OMB to increase CDO funding flexibilities and direct resources.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CDOs should work with OMB to clarify responsibilities and expectations.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Congress should remove the statutory sunset of the CDO Council.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The CDO Council should work to create an ecosystem of data-literate and data-fluent workers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CDOs should emphasize their role as designated leaders to promote training and data fluency among staff of departments.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The CDO Council should work with the OMB to ensure that forthcoming implementation guidance to agencies on data inventories prioritizes machine readability and interoperability.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CDOs should focus on data sharing standards that facilitate interoperability, data linkage, and privacy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Publicly accessible data must be prioritized.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CDOs can improve communication about how they demonstrate the value of using data.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CDOs should conduct regular maturity assessments to accurately gauge existing data capacity and needs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The CDO Council should create a permanent data ethics working group to ensure the Data Ethics framework continuously meets emerging needs, to provide resources and guidance to agencies, and to partner with relevant professional associations for ongoing education and training on data ethics.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The CDO Council should work with CIOs to facilitate the adoption of appropriate modernized technology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Luke Fretwell</name></author><category term="[&quot;Digital&quot;, &quot;Data&quot;]" /><summary type="html">In response to a Chief Data Officers Council call for public feedback, the Data Coalition shared its recommendations on how the federal government can best leverage data.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">NIST wants public feedback on cybersecurity labeling for consumer software</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/radar/nist-public-input-cybersecurity-consumer-software-labeling" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="NIST wants public feedback on cybersecurity labeling for consumer software" /><published>2021-11-03T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-11-15T13:24:01-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/radar/nist-public-input-cybersecurity-consumer-software-labeling</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/radar/nist-public-input-cybersecurity-consumer-software-labeling">&lt;p&gt;The National Institute of Standards and Technology has drafted a set of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nist.gov/itl/executive-order-improving-nations-cybersecurity/consumer-software-criteria&quot;&gt;cybersecurity criteria&lt;/a&gt; to help consumers make more informed software purchasing decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NIST says it doesn’t intend to create a formal standard, but hopes to create a voluntary labeling system that shows the software “incorporates a baseline level of security measures.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From NIST:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The document, formally titled &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nist.gov/document/draft-baseline-criteria-consumer-software-cybersecurity-labeling&quot;&gt;Draft Baseline Criteria for Consumer Software Cybersecurity Labeling&lt;/a&gt;, forms part of NIST’s response to the May 12, 2021, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2021/05/17/2021-10460/improving-the-nations-cybersecurity&quot;&gt;Executive Order (EO) 14028 on Improving the Nation’s Cybersecurity&lt;/a&gt;. The EO specifies that NIST “shall identify secure software development practices or criteria for a consumer software labeling program” — criteria that reflect a baseline level of cybersecurity and that focus on ease of use for consumers. (The EO also instructs NIST to initiate a labeling effort on the cybersecurity aspects of consumer devices associated with the Internet of Things, which the present publication does not address.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the announcement, NIST acknowledged the challenges of a security labeling system for a wide array of technology solutions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Part of the challenge is the sheer vastness and variety of the consumer software landscape. Software forms an integral part of most consumers’ lives, and it is subject to vulnerabilities that place the users’ safety, property and productivity at risk — but there is no one-size-fits-all approach to cybersecurity that can be applied to all types of consumer software. The cybersecurity considerations for a smartphone game could differ greatly from, for example, those applied to a banking app. Yet a security label aimed at consumers will need to communicate simply and directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comments on the draft document are due by December 16, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Luke Fretwell</name></author><category term="[&quot;Digital&quot;, &quot;Security&quot;]" /><summary type="html">The National Institute of Standards and Technology has drafted a set of cybersecurity criteria to help consumers make more informed software purchasing decisions.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Denice Ross named federal chief data scientist</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/radar/denice-ross-named-federal-chief-data-scientist" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Denice Ross named federal chief data scientist" /><published>2021-11-03T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-11-15T13:24:01-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/radar/denice-ross-named-federal-chief-data-scientist</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/radar/denice-ross-named-federal-chief-data-scientist">&lt;p&gt;Denice Ross was named as U.S. chief data scientist at the White House Office of Science and Technology Policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the anouncement on her blog:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The current moment is an extraordinary policy window for the Biden-Harris Administration to shore up our nation’s data infrastructure and reconfigure the public decision-making process so data scientists can best support the design and implementation of policies to improve the lives of all Americans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As I head into this new role as Chief Data Scientist, I’m focused on addressing these questions: What data do we need to design an equitable recovery? How will we use that data responsibly and to ensure we are building back better? What can we do to support the Federal, Tribal, state, and local data practitioners so they can help deliver better outcomes for the American people?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The mission of the U.S. Chief Data Scientist is to responsibly unleash the power of data to benefit all Americans. I’m eager to get started and look forward to collaborating with data innovators already working inside of Federal government and at the State, Tribal, and local level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow Ross’ official government Twitter handle at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/deniceross46&quot;&gt;@DeniceRoss46&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://denicewross.blog/2021/11/03/rejoining-federal-service-as-the-next-u-s-chief-data-scientist/&quot;&gt;Rejoining Federal Service as the next U.S. Chief Data Scientist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Luke Fretwell</name></author><category term="[&quot;Digital&quot;]" /><summary type="html">Denice Ross was named as U.S. chief data scientist at the White House Office of Science and Technology Policy.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2021 Federal Plain Language Report Card released</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/radar/2021-federal-plain-language-report-card" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2021 Federal Plain Language Report Card released" /><published>2021-11-02T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-11-15T13:24:01-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/radar/2021-federal-plain-language-report-card</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/radar/2021-federal-plain-language-report-card">&lt;p&gt;The Center for Plain Language issued its yearly &lt;a href=&quot;https://centerforplainlanguage.org/2021-federal-plain-language-report-card/&quot;&gt;plain language report card&lt;/a&gt;. This year’s focus was on the main Freedom of Information Act request and Coronavirus pages of 21 executive branch agencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Agencies earned grades between A and F for both organizational compliance, covering the staffing, training, and annual reporting required by the Plain Writing Act, and writing quality, focusing on how easy it is to find, understand, and use information the public needs,” said the Center for Plain Language referencing the 2021 report card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On writing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Overall the average writing grade was a B-, unchanged from last year. But this year’s average was pulled down by poor marks for the FOIA Request pages, where the average grade was a C+.  Within that average is a far more positive story:  agencies are doing a better job communicating about the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On compliance:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Two-thirds of agencies surveyed this year earned an A on organizational compliance (how well they meet the staffing, training, and annual reporting requirements of the 2010 Plain Writing Act).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Center for Plain Language included examplary examples of FOIA and Coronavirus pages to support those looking for guidance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://centerforplainlanguage.org/2021-federal-plain-language-report-card/&quot;&gt;2021 Federal Plain Language Report Card&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Luke Fretwell</name></author><category term="[&quot;Digital&quot;, &quot;Design&quot;, &quot;Inclusion&quot;]" /><summary type="html">The Center for Plain Language issued its yearly plain language report card. This year’s focus was on the main Freedom of Information Act request and Coronavirus pages of 21 executive branch agencies.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">National Intelligence director speaks on diversity, equity, inclusion, accessibility efforts</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/radar/dni-deia-opening-remarks" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="National Intelligence director speaks on diversity, equity, inclusion, accessibility efforts" /><published>2021-10-28T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-11-15T13:24:01-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/radar/dni-deia-opening-remarks</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/radar/dni-deia-opening-remarks">&lt;p&gt;In an opening statement to U.S. House Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence, Director of National Intelligence Avril Haines shared the agency’s “work we have ahead of us to advance diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Haines:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“While we have exceptional leaders within the IC who are committed to promoting DEIA, many of whom have worked hard to achieve the progress we have made thus far on these issues over the last many years, we know we have a great deal of work ahead of us. These leaders know that it is not only essential to our mission and our values but to who we are as a nation. Promoting diversity – ensuring that we reflect the country we serve – is a responsibility we carry as public servants.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Moreover, it is fundamental to our national security.  Ensuring that we have an IC 
workforce made up of people who think differently, see problems differently, and 
overcome challenges differently, is a prerequisite to our success. Their creativity 
makes us smarter, more innovative, and more successful.  And that makes our 
nation safer and more secure against the array of adversaries and the foreign 
threats we face.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Haines emphasized the agency can do better, outlined its work to date and “what we’re doing to change the situation.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In the IC we know how to work together to support the nation’s objectives. Congress created ODNI to do this, and we are bringing that approach to our efforts to increase diversity, equity, inclusion and accessibility,” said Haines. “This spirit is quintessentially American - to recognize our imperfections and decide we can be better – to see we have the power to make ourselves better – to work toward a brighter vision of what might be, what could be, and what will be. We are resolute in this purpose and I know we will be successful.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dni.gov/files/ODNI/documents/2021-10-27-DEIA-Opening-Statement.pdf&quot;&gt;Full statement.&lt;/a&gt; (.pdf)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Luke Fretwell</name></author><category term="[&quot;Inclusion&quot;, &quot;Security&quot;]" /><summary type="html">In an opening statement to U.S. House Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence, Director of National Intelligence Avril Haines shared the agency’s “work we have ahead of us to advance diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Open security controls: NIST officially releases OSCAL 1.0.0</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021-06-08-nist-officially-releases-oscal-1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Open security controls: NIST officially releases OSCAL 1.0.0" /><published>2021-06-08T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-11-15T13:24:01-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/nist-officially-releases-oscal-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021-06-08-nist-officially-releases-oscal-1/">&lt;p&gt;The National Institute of Standards and Technology officially released &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.nist.gov/OSCAL/&quot;&gt;Open Security Controls Assessment Language 1.0.0&lt;/a&gt;, a federal government effort to standardize authorization packages and streamline security reviews using a common machine-readable language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fedramp.gov/blog/2021-06-08-NISTs-OSCAL-1-0-0-Release/&quot;&gt;FedRAMP blog&lt;/a&gt; announcing the benefits of the release:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cloud service providers can “create their System Security Plans more rapidly and accurately, validating much of their content before submission to the government for review.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Federal agencies can “expedite their reviews of the FedRAMP security authorization packages.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Third Party Assessment Organizations (3PAOs) can “automate the planning, execution, and reporting of cloud assessment activities.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The idea of developing OSCAL was fueled by my frustration around the lack of transparency into cloud services’ security posture, in particular, from the cloud consumers’ perspective,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nist.gov/blogs/cybersecurity-insights/foundation-interoperable-and-portable-security-automation-revealed&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; Michaela Iorga on the NIST blog. “From the beginning, OSCAL was envisioned to be the foundation for interoperable and portable security automation in support of Authorization to Operate processes for all types of systems, not just cloud-based systems – a very challenging task. Because of this challenge, our NIST team partnered in 2016 with GSA/FedRAMP to research and develop OSCAL – the standardized, openly-available, foundational representation of the security information in support of security automation and of risk management frameworks in general.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/usnistgov/OSCAL/releases/tag/v1.0.0&quot;&gt;OSCAL 1.0.0 release notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/usnistgov/OSCAL&quot;&gt;OSCAL GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.nist.gov/OSCAL/&quot;&gt;OSCAL website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Luke Fretwell</name></author><category term="[&quot;Security&quot;, &quot;Open&quot;]" /><summary type="html">The National Institute of Standards and Technology officially released Open Security Controls Assessment Language 1.0.0, a federal government effort to standardize authorization packages and streamline security reviews using a common machine-readable language.</summary></entry></feed>