<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-03-16T08:52:02-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">GovFresh</title><subtitle>Public service with and by the people.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">National Science Foundation wants help building open culture</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/radar/nsf-pathways-to-enable-open-source-ecosystems" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="National Science Foundation wants help building open culture" /><published>2022-03-16T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-03-16T08:52:02-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/radar/nsf-pathways-to-enable-open-source-ecosystems</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/radar/nsf-pathways-to-enable-open-source-ecosystems">&lt;p&gt;The National Science Foundation wants proposals to support a new agnecy program “to harness the power of open-source development for the creation of new technology solutions to problems of national and societal importance.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The program is called &lt;a href=&quot;https://beta.nsf.gov/funding/opportunities/pathways-enable-open-source-ecosystems-pose&quot;&gt;Pathways to Enable Open-Source Ecosystems&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NSF will host an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nsf.gov/events/event_summ.jsp?cntn_id=304552&amp;amp;org=NSF&quot;&gt;informational webinar&lt;/a&gt; on March 23. &lt;a href=&quot;https://nsf.zoomgov.com/webinar/register/WN_GDUveT2ZTBG4c-tNxaODoA&quot;&gt;Register.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the &lt;a href=&quot;https://beta.nsf.gov/funding/opportunities/pathways-enable-open-source-ecosystems-pose&quot;&gt;POSE website&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The purpose of the program is to harness the power of open-source development for the creation of new technology solutions to problems of national and societal importance. Many NSF-funded research projects result in publicly accessible, modifiable, and distributable open-sourced software, hardware or data platforms that catalyze further innovation. In some cases, an open-source product is widely adopted and forms the basis for a self-sustaining open-source ecosystem (OSE) comprises a distributed community of developers and a broad base of users across academia, industry and government. The goal of the POSE program is to fund new OSE managing organizations, each responsible for the creation and maintenance of infrastructure needed for efficient and secure operation of an OSE based around a specific open-source product or class of products. The early and intentional formation of such managing organizations is expected to ensure more secure open-source products, increased coordination of developer contributions, and a more focused route to impactful technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Importantly, the POSE program is not intended to fund the development of open-source research products, including tools and artifacts. The POSE program is also not intended to fund existing well-resourced open-source communities and ecosystems. Instead, the program aims to fund new managing organizations that catalyze community-driven development and growth of the subject OSEs. The expected outcomes of the POSE program are (1) to grow the community of researchers who develop and contribute to OSE efforts, and (2) to enable pathways for the development of collaborative OSEs that could lead to new technology products or services that have broad societal impacts. OSEs can stem from any areas of research supported by NSF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>Luke Fretwell</name></author><category term="[&quot;Digital&quot;, &quot;Community&quot;, &quot;Open&quot;]" /><summary type="html">The National Science Foundation wants proposals to support a new agnecy program “to harness the power of open-source development for the creation of new technology solutions to problems of national and societal importance.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Defense Department: Choose ‘OSS solutions before buying proprietary’</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/radar/dod-open-source-software-memo" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Defense Department: Choose ‘OSS solutions before buying proprietary’" /><published>2022-02-07T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-02-07T16:17:15-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/radar/dod-open-source-software-memo</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/radar/dod-open-source-software-memo">&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Defense Department released a memo that gives agency direction on open source software usage, citing a preference for and the benefits of its adoption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the January 24 &lt;a href=&quot;https://dodcio.defense.gov/Portals/0/Documents/Library/SoftwareDev-OpenSource.pdf&quot;&gt;memo&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Department must follow an “Adopt, Buy, Create” approach to software preferentially adopting existing government or OSS solutions before buying proprietary offerings, and only creating new non-commercial software when no off-the-shelf solutions are adequate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As “an experiment in open source,” the Defense Department &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.defense.gov/News/Releases/Release/Article/1092364/dod-announces-the-launch-of-codemil-an-experiment-in-open-source/&quot;&gt;launched Code.mil&lt;/a&gt; in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is a direct avenue for the department to tap into a worldwide community of developers to collectively speed up and strengthen the software development process,” said the Defense Deparment at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Modern software is open sourced software (OSS),” says the Defense Department on its &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.mil/&quot;&gt;Code.mil&lt;/a&gt; website. “The creative contribution of individual developers to help solve complex problems of impact is largely untapped by DoD. We must more actively participate in the open source and free software communities if we are to truly reap the benefits of OSS.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Luke Fretwell</name></author><category term="[&quot;Digital&quot;, &quot;Open&quot;]" /><summary type="html">The U.S. Defense Department released a memo that gives agency direction on open source software usage, citing a preference for and the benefits of its adoption.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">California shares beta version of its new design system</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/radar/california-design-system-beta" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="California shares beta version of its new design system" /><published>2022-01-31T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-01-31T16:21:26-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/radar/california-design-system-beta</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/radar/california-design-system-beta">&lt;p&gt;The state of California launched a beta version of its new design system, that aims to make it “easy for state digital teams to build accessible, consistent, and performant services and products to meet Californians’ needs.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About the project:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It can be challenging to connect government services to Californians who need them most. We have to consider a wide range of experiences, abilities, education, and technical literacy. With the State of California’s Design System, we help make digital information and services easier to use. The Design System increases equity, unity, compassion, and trust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea of the design system was first initiated by the state’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://alpha.ca.gov/&quot;&gt;Alpha project&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Alpha was the first effort to reimagine how government understands, builds and provides digital services. The primary goal was to create a better digital experience for all Californians. The CA.gov Alpha team adopted agile principles allowing them to quickly iterate on feedback while blogging their story out in the open.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://designsystem.webstandards.ca.gov/&quot;&gt;California Design System&lt;/a&gt; includes &lt;a href=&quot;https://designsystem.webstandards.ca.gov/principles/&quot;&gt;design principles&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://designsystem.webstandards.ca.gov/style/content/&quot;&gt;content and design guides&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://designsystem.webstandards.ca.gov/components/&quot;&gt;component library&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://cannabis.ca.gov/&quot;&gt;Department of Cannabis Control&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://covid19.ca.gov/&quot;&gt;COVID-19&lt;/a&gt; websites are now using the design system.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Luke Fretwell</name></author><category term="[&quot;Open&quot;, &quot;Design&quot;]" /><summary type="html">The state of California launched a beta version of its new design system, that aims to make it “easy for state digital teams to build accessible, consistent, and performant services and products to meet Californians’ needs.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">In-Q-Tel built an open source software ‘nutrition label’</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/radar/in-q-tel-open-source-software-nutrition-label" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="In-Q-Tel built an open source software ‘nutrition label’" /><published>2022-01-26T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-01-26T21:05:46-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/radar/in-q-tel-open-source-software-nutrition-label</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/radar/in-q-tel-open-source-software-nutrition-label">&lt;p&gt;In-Q-Tel built a “nutrition label” prototype that gives developers insight into the health of open source software packages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In-Q-Tel &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iqt.org/open-source-software-nutrition-labels-an-ai-assurance-application/&quot;&gt;asks&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If software developers and software program managers had access to information about the health and security of specific open source software packages – like shoppers in a grocery store looking at food nutrition labels – would they be empowered to make better choices about which software packages to use?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For context, In-Q-Tel created a &lt;a href=&quot;https://trui4.csb.app/&quot;&gt;nutrition label for FakeFinder&lt;/a&gt;, an open source tool that analyzes whether a video contains deepfakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indicators used for the label include package totals for contributors, maintainers, dependencies and versions, as well as license type, funding resources, package health scores and days since last release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code for the OSS nutrition label is available at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/IQTLabs/OSSNutritionLabelPrototypes&quot;&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Luke Fretwell</name></author><category term="[&quot;Open&quot;]" /><summary type="html">In-Q-Tel built a “nutrition label” prototype that gives developers insight into the health of open source software packages.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Citizen satisfaction with federal government services drops to all-time low</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/radar/2021-asci-federal-government-report" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Citizen satisfaction with federal government services drops to all-time low" /><published>2022-01-25T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-01-25T17:37:09-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/radar/2021-asci-federal-government-report</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/radar/2021-asci-federal-government-report">&lt;p&gt;Results from the annual American Customer Satisfaction Index survey say public satisfaction with U.S. federal government services is down 2.6% to 63.4%, the lowest rating ever recorded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The results are based on interviews with 2,387 people who were asked to evaluate their 2021 experiences with federal government services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theacsi.org/news-and-resources/customer-satisfaction-reports/reports-2021/acsi-federal-government-report-2021&quot;&gt;announcement&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The ACSI federal government model measures four primary drivers of citizen satisfaction that are quality attributes which represent the most relevant performance areas of government agencies and services. Among these drivers of satisfaction, all four decline between 2020 and 2021: efficiency and ease of government processes (-5% to 63), ease of accessing and clarity of information (-3% to 67), the courtesy and professionalism of customer service (-1% to 73), and perceptions of government website quality (-1% to 70). Collectively, these declines represent a broad erosion of the quality of federal government services experienced by citizens in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Satisfaction by political affiliation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Looking at year-over-year trends from 2020 to 2021 by party affiliation, both Democrats (-4% to 65) and Republicans (-2% to 64) show declines in citizen satisfaction. The relatively small group of “Other Party” supporters (-13% to 54) also expresses much lower satisfaction in 2021 although this group’s smaller sample size yields greater year-to-year variability. Only Independents who indicate no political party affiliation (+2% to 63) show a small increase in satisfaction for 2021. Nevertheless, the broad decline in citizen satisfaction across all respondents who indicate a political affiliation—including Democrats, Republicans, and Other Party supporters—reinforces the existence of a widespread erosion in the perceived quality of government output across citizens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theacsi.org/images/stories/images/govsatscores/22jan_FED-GOV-Report.pdf&quot;&gt;ACSI Federal Government Report 2021&lt;/a&gt; (.pdf)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Luke Fretwell</name></author><category term="[&quot;Customer experience&quot;]" /><summary type="html">Results from the annual American Customer Satisfaction Index survey say public satisfaction with U.S. federal government services is down 2.6% to 63.4%, the lowest rating ever recorded.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">NASA Spinoff 2022 features ventures using agency IP that ‘boost the economy, protect the planet, and save lives’</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/radar/nasa-2022-spinoffs" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="NASA Spinoff 2022 features ventures using agency IP that ‘boost the economy, protect the planet, and save lives’" /><published>2022-01-24T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-01-24T19:19:20-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/radar/nasa-2022-spinoffs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/radar/nasa-2022-spinoffs">&lt;p&gt;NASA’s Technology Transfer Program published its &lt;a href=&quot;https://spinoff.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/2022-01/Spinoff.2022.pdf&quot;&gt;Spinoff 2022&lt;/a&gt; issue that “tells the stories of companies, start-ups, and entrepreneurs transforming these innovations into cutting-edge products and services that boost the economy, protect the planet, and save lives.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nasa.gov/press-release/nasa-spinoffs-help-fight-coronavirus-clean-pollution-grow-food-more&quot;&gt;announcement&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Spinoff 2022 features more than 45 companies using NASA technology to advance manufacturing techniques, detoxify polluted soil, improve weather forecasting, and even clean the air to slow the spread of viruses, including coronavirus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“These NASA technologies are not only giving companies and entrepreneurs a competitive edge in their own industries but are also helping to shape budding industries, such as commercial lunar landers,” said Daniel Lockney, Technology Transfer program executive at NASA Headquarters in Washington. “NASA is much more than rocket launches and astronauts. We’re about improving the quality of life for people all around the world.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Luke Fretwell</name></author><category term="[&quot;Digital&quot;, &quot;Open&quot;]" /><summary type="html">NASA’s Technology Transfer Program published its Spinoff 2022 issue that “tells the stories of companies, start-ups, and entrepreneurs transforming these innovations into cutting-edge products and services that boost the economy, protect the planet, and save lives.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">U.S. government, technology community advance open source security collaboration efforts</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/radar/white-house-open-source-security-summit" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="U.S. government, technology community advance open source security collaboration efforts" /><published>2022-01-14T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-01-14T10:24:08-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/radar/white-house-open-source-security-summit</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/radar/white-house-open-source-security-summit">&lt;p&gt;In the wake of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Log4j&quot;&gt;Log4j vulnerability&lt;/a&gt;, the White House met with technology companies and organizations to discuss how the federal government and industry can better partner on open source security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prior to the White House Open Source Software Security Summit, a senior administration official &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cyberscoop.com/white-house-log4j-open-source-software-security/&quot;&gt;told CyberScoop&lt;/a&gt;, “Building on the Log4j incident, the objective of this meeting is to facilitate an important discussion to improve the security of open source software — and to brainstorm how new collaboration could rapidly drive improvements.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to CyberScoop, the full tech participant list included Akamai, Amazon, Apache Software Foundation, Apple, Cloudflare, Facebook/Meta, GitHub, Google, IBM, Linux Open Source Foundation, Microsoft, Oracle, RedHat and VMware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;U.S. Commerce Secretary Gina Raimondo said the National Institute of Standards and Technology is working to gather ideas from technology and open source communities on how best to work together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“NIST intends to soon release a Request for Information asking stakeholders – people like you – how it can improve its cybersecurity efforts,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.commerce.gov/news/speeches/2022/01/remarks-us-commerce-secretary-gina-m-raimondo-white-house-open-source&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; Raimondo. “This will help ensure that NIST is partnering effectively with both the private and public sectors on cybersecurity, including open-source software.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Companies and organizations released statements expressing their commitment to collaborating with government to build stronger communities related to open source security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openssf.org/blog/2022/01/13/the-openssf-and-the-linux-foundation-address-software-supply-chain-security-challenges-at-white-house-summit/&quot;&gt;OpenSSF / Linux Foundation&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The open source ecosystem will need to work together to further cybersecurity research, training, analysis and remediation of defects found in critical open source software projects. These plans were met with positive feedback and a growing, collective commitment to take meaningful action. Following the recent log4j crisis, the time has never been more pressing for public and private collaboration to ensure that open source software components and the software supply chains they flow through demonstrate the highest cybersecurity integrity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.blog/2022-01-13-open-source-software-security-summit-securing-the-worlds-code-together/&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We see tremendous opportunity ahead to help the community realize a safer and more secure future for software. Through partnerships with governments, academia, developers, and other organizations, we can better protect and support the developers and software that power our world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.google/technology/safety-security/making-open-source-software-safer-and-more-secure/&quot;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Many leading companies and organizations don’t recognize how many parts of their critical infrastructure depend on open source. That’s why it’s essential that we see more public and private investment in keeping that ecosystem healthy and secure. … Given the importance of digital infrastructure in our lives, it’s time to start thinking of it in the same way we do our physical infrastructure. Open source software is a connective tissue for much of the online world — it deserves the same focus and funding we give to our roads and bridges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>Luke Fretwell</name></author><category term="[&quot;Digital&quot;, &quot;Open&quot;, &quot;Security&quot;]" /><summary type="html">In the wake of the Log4j vulnerability, the White House met with technology companies and organizations to discuss how the federal government and industry can better partner on open source security.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">California is working with six states to re-use code from its vaccine records portal</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/radar/california-digital-vaccine-record" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="California is working with six states to re-use code from its vaccine records portal" /><published>2022-01-09T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-01-09T16:42:32-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/radar/california-digital-vaccine-record</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/radar/california-digital-vaccine-record">&lt;p&gt;California Chief Technology Innovation Officer Rick Klau reports that 6.5 million residents have downloaded more than 11 million digital vaccine records from the state’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://myvaccinerecord.cdph.ca.gov/&quot;&gt;vaccine record portal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Klau says the state made the portal code base publicly available for re-use, and Washington state re-purposed it for its own vaccine records website. The state is working with other states to do the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the &lt;a href=&quot;https://techblog.cdt.ca.gov/2022/01/californians-have-downloaded-over-11-million-digital-vaccine-records/&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In September 2021, we released all of the code we wrote for our DCVR Portal to the public domain. Our hope at the time was that other states might take our code and implement their own system for their residents. Less than two months later, Washington State did just that, releasing WAVerify to enable Washington residents to retrieve their own digital vaccine record. Washington went a step further, making a number of improvements to our code, including adding dozens of additional translations to make the service more accessible for additional communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As we look ahead to 2022, we’re in touch with another six states who plan on following Washington’s lead, bringing code originally developed in California to even more Americans in the next few months. We put together a playbook that documented some of what we learned this year as we built and shipped the DCVR Portal, and expect other states may find it instructive as they explore doing something similar to what we did in California.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>Luke Fretwell</name></author><category term="[&quot;Digital&quot;, &quot;Open&quot;]" /><summary type="html">California Chief Technology Innovation Officer Rick Klau reports that 6.5 million residents have downloaded more than 11 million digital vaccine records from the state’s vaccine record portal.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CDO Council retrospects 2021, publishes data playbook</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/radar/cdo-council-2021-playbook" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CDO Council retrospects 2021, publishes data playbook" /><published>2022-01-03T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-01-09T16:42:32-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/radar/cdo-council-2021-playbook</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/radar/cdo-council-2021-playbook">&lt;p&gt;The Federal Chief Data Officers Council &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cdo.gov/news/celebrating-2021/&quot;&gt;shared&lt;/a&gt; its 2021 accomplishments and published a playbook to help CDOs “lead data-driven transformation” within their agencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the playbook:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;CDOs must seize opportunities to leverage data as a strategic asset within their
organization, otherwise, the CDO faces the risk of becoming a compliance driven
position. The CDO should first focus on finding opportunities to promote
the sharing and access of data within their agencies. They must build critical
relationships and show value in the near-term through “quick wins,” as data
governance and master data management programs take longer to implement
and demonstrate results. It is a hard job with a value proposition not consistently
appreciated and with challenges that are critical to overcome to properly serve their stakeholders and the American people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://resources.data.gov/assets/documents/CDO_Playbook_2021.pdf&quot;&gt;Playbook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Luke Fretwell</name></author><category term="[&quot;Data&quot;, &quot;Digital&quot;]" /><summary type="html">The Federal Chief Data Officers Council shared its 2021 accomplishments and published a playbook to help CDOs “lead data-driven transformation” within their agencies.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Public gives NASA ideas for engaging untapped communities</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/radar/nasa-engagement-underserved-communities" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Public gives NASA ideas for engaging untapped communities" /><published>2021-12-09T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-01-09T16:42:32-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/radar/nasa-engagement-underserved-communities</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/radar/nasa-engagement-underserved-communities">&lt;p&gt;NASA received 195 comments from the public in respose to a June 2021 request for information entitled, “Advancing Racial Equity and Support for Underserved Communities in NASA Programs, Contracts and Grants.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nasa.gov/press-release/public-provides-nasa-ideas-for-engaging-untapped-communities&quot;&gt;release&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;NASA requested public feedback about how it can provide underserved communities with equal access to the opportunities the agency creates. NASA specifically asked for feedback on possible opportunities to leverage NASA assets to help underserved communities, and barriers to accessing current NASA grants, programs, and procurements. The agency also worked to engage with organizations and individuals from underserved and underrepresented communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/atoms/files/rfi_response_for_eo_13985-11-23-21.pdf&quot;&gt;Responses to Mission Equity RFI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Luke Fretwell</name></author><category term="[&quot;Community&quot;, &quot;Data&quot;]" /><summary type="html">NASA received 195 comments from the public in respose to a June 2021 request for information entitled, “Advancing Racial Equity and Support for Underserved Communities in NASA Programs, Contracts and Grants.”</summary></entry></feed>